<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Companies | Sam Hamilton]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/blog/categories/companies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-27T11:11:22+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sam Hamilton]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon: The Hidden Empire]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/blog/2011/05/31/amazon-the-hidden-empire/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-31T00:21:06+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/blog/2011/05/31/amazon-the-hidden-empire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A comprehensive look at the business of Amazon.com</p>

<p><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/faberNovel/amazoncom-the-hidden-empire">http://www.slideshare.net/faberNovel/amazoncom-the-hidden-empire</a>">http://www.slideshare.net/faberNovel/amazoncom-the-hidden-empire">http://www.slideshare.net/faberNovel/amazoncom-the-hidden-empire</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to run Banks]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/blog/2010/10/10/how-to-run-banks/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-10T20:11:28+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/blog/2010/10/10/how-to-run-banks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just read this interesting piece on the New York Times website where due to the change in how the companies that work on Wall Street have changed their corporate structure has had massive effects on how they work but the bit that really stuck out was</p>

<p><blockquote><p>When Goldman went public in 1999, unlike other firms it decided that a group of its 400 or so top executives would get paid not out of the firm’s revenues, but instead from the firm’s pretax profits. If the firm has no pretax profits in any given year, these executives get (only) their six-figure salaries, not the tens of millions in bonuses they count on.</p></p><p><p>As a result, the senior brass at Goldman is hyperfocused on making sure the firm is always profitable, and it always has been. This may very well be the precise reason that Goldman alone saw the brewing mortgage meltdown and did something about it.</p></p><p><p>When other firms were losing billions of dollars in 2007 as the mortgage market exploded, Goldman made $17.6 billion in pretax profits, one of its most profitable years ever, and its top three executives split around $200 million. You would think the rest of Wall Street would emulate Goldman’s approach to compensating its top executives. But it hasn’t.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>It a good read if you have 10 mins &ndash; <a href="http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/2010/10/07/make-wall-street-risk-it-all/">Opinionator: Make Wall Street Risk It All</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/blog/2010/10/07/a-new-week/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-07T08:31:56+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/blog/2010/10/07/a-new-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So the last day in September was my last day working for my employeer &ndash; enough said.</p>

<p>So today after a weeks rest I begin my next journey, one that has been calling me for oh&hellip;14 years or so. I am going to start a webhosting company. Yep I know I am mad, everyone and their brother is doing it, already done it, already got the biggest and best company in the world. Yep I know, don&rsquo;t care because I want one too &ndash; I want to know if I can make a living out of probably one of the toughest parts of the internet.</p>

<p>Now some people I have spoken to have said I need a niche, well I am not so sure that I do. I think that webhosting companies should not specialise in what they do except they should host the web &ndash; think about that for a second what does that mean, what does that take? Its a lot of things and different things all at the same time. They should not think that people or companies are all the same &ndash; everyone is different and they should not try and offer the same experience to everyone either as that is not going to fit. The trouble is that getting to this place where my hosting company can do all the things it should do for its customers is going to take time, lots of time. Why? Because only some of this exists and the rest needs to be created but today I am going to start out with something that really does not fit everyone and just get somewhere to prove that I can 1. do this myself and 2. it can earn enough money that I don&rsquo;t need to get a job while it grows (that would be super boring!)</p>

<p>Hardware bought, datacenter picked, operating system chosen, hosting software purchased &ndash; time to pull it all together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video from Jeff Bezos about Amazon and Zappos]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/blog/2009/09/07/video-from-jeff-bezos-about-amazon-and-zappos/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-07T18:46:17+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.samhamilton.co.uk/blog/2009/09/07/video-from-jeff-bezos-about-amazon-and-zappos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Great video from Jeff BeZos about Amazon and what his keys to success are:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hxX_Q5CnaA">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hxX_Q5CnaA</a>">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hxX_Q5CnaA">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-hxX_Q5CnaA</a></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
